Guide to the March, Middagh, and Sands families property records 1974.038
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Release from Coles family to Joshua S. March, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Release, part of Mortgaged Premises, conveying parcels on Brooklyn Heights, from John B. Coles, Isaac U. Coles, William F. Coles, trusees of their sister Elizabeth F. Morris, the wife of Thomas A. Morris, under the will of their father John B. Coles deceased, to Joshua S. March, re: an 1833 indenture of mortgage made with Samuel B.M. Sands and his wife Magdalen Sands, the release signed by the Coles Brothers and witnessed by W.W. Townsend, Alfred Stevens, and Charles E. Bulkeley.
- Mortgage between Joshua S. March and the Long Island Bank, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Mortgage made between Joshua S. March and his wife Magdalen March and the Long Island Bank, conveying land in Brooklyn, re: a debt owed to the Bank by Joshua S. March, the mortgage signed by Joshua and Magdalen, witnessed by Theodore Eames and Adrian Hegeman.
- Two releases from Coles family to Magdalen March, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Two releases, parts of Mortgaged Premises, conveying parcels on Brooklyn Heights, from John B. Coles, Isaac U. Coles, William F. Coles, trusees of theier sister Elizabeth F. Morris, the wife of Thomas A. Morris, under the will of their father John B. Coles deceased, to Magdalen March, re: an 1833 indenture of mortgage made with Magdalen and her husband at that time, Samuel B.M. Sands, the release signed by the Coles Brothers and witnessed by Joseph Strong, Nathaniel Jarvis, and Adrian Hegeman.
- Release from Long Island Bank to Magdalen March, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Release, part of Mortgaged Premises, re: the 1842 Mortgage made between Joshua S. March and his wife Magdalen March and the Long Island Bank, the Bank now releasing certain parcels upon payment from Magdalen March, the release signed by Leffert Lefferts, president of the Bank, witnessed by Sidney C. Herbert and Adrian Hegeman.
- Mortgage between Martha Middagh and the estate of Magdalen March, 1846 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Mortgage made between Martha Middagh (née Martha Van Nostrand) and Cyrus Porter Smith and Abraham Van Nostrand, executors of the will of Martha's daughter Magdalen March deceased, conveying four lots on Brooklyn Heights, the mortgage signed by Martha Middagh, witnessed by Charles J. Lowrey and John M. Hicks.
- Mortgage between the estate of Magdalen March and John M. Sands, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Assignment of Mortgage whereby Cyrus Porter Smith (being now sole executor of the will of Magdalen March deceased, Abraham Van Nostrand having died on 5 February 1848) transfers the above mortgage to John M. Sands, the assignment signed and sealed by Smith and witnessed by Charles J. Lowrey and John M. Hicks.
- Lease from John M. Sands to John R. Luckey, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Lease conveying premises at 96 Middagh street from John M. Sands to John R. Luckey. Mentions neighbors Hetty Furman and Henry Moody. Signed and later cancelled by both parties.
- Mortgage between Jesse C. Dann and John M. Sand, 1850 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Mortgage made between Jesse C. Dann and John M. Sands, conveying land at Sackets Harbor, Jefferson Co., NY. Unsigned, possibly a draft.
- Report of the Kings County Board of Supervisors' committee, 1838 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Report of the Kings County Board of Supervisors' committee, copy (the original signed by Joseph Conselyea, Tunis G. Bergen, and Jeremiah Lott), furnished by Jeremiah Lott (clerk of the Board), re: the acts and proceedings of Nathan B. Morse and Andrew Emmans, "Commissioners appointed to loan the portion of the United States Revenue to which the County of Kings is entitled," with a detailed schedule containing "the names of the individuals to whom loans have been made, amounts to each, security, etc.," which lists 65 mortgages involving 107 persons, also describing the locations of their properties giving names of some of their neighbors.
- Mortgage on lease between Samuel B.M. Sands and the Brooklyn Fire Insurance Company, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Mortgage on lease made between Samuel B.M. Sands and the Brooklyn Fire Insurance Company, conveying a lot in Brooklyn Heights, re: an 1826 lease made to Sands by Losee Van Nostrand (acting as guardian to "the infant children and heirs at law of Aert Middagh dec'd," the 1830 mortgage signed by Sands, witnessed by Edward M.M. Clarke and Abraham Vanderveer.
- Bond between Samuel B.M. Sands, William M. Sands, and Ralph Patchen and the Brooklyn Fire Insurance Company, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Bond between Samuel B.M. Sands, William M. Sands, and Ralph Patchen, of Brooklyn, and the Brooklyn Fire Insurance Company, signed by the debtors, witnessed by Sidney C. Herbert and J. Laurence.
- Release between Globe Insurance Company and Matthias Bruen, 1833 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Release, part of Mortgaged Premises, made between the Globe Insurance Company and Matthias Bruen of Perth Amboy, NJ, re: 8 lots in Brooklyn, signed by Henry Rankin, president of the Globe Insurance Co., and witnessed by Robert G. Rankin, Abraham Asten, and Abraham Vanderveer.
- Release between the Long Island Insurance Company and Joshua S. March, 1839 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  Release, part of Mortgaged Premises, made between the Long Island Insurance Company and Joshua S. March, conveying a lot on Brooklyn Heights, re: an 1834 mortgage made by Samuel B.M. Sands and his wife Magdalen Sands, the release signed by Joseph Sprague, president of the Long Island Insurance Company, Henry Cruse Murphy, and Charles E. Bulkeley.
- Release from William G. Ward to Magdalen March, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  Release of Judgement conveying 4 lots in Brooklyn from William G. Ward to Magdalen March, re: a judgement obtained by Charles E. Quincey against Joshua S. March deceased, signed by Ward, Abraham Van Nostrand, S. Alpheus Smithe (Smith), and Adrian Hegeman.
- Surrogate Court Records re: Mitchell, circa 1809 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  These are three near identical copies of a petition made by Dorothy Mitchell (Mitchel) as administratrix of the estate of her husband Frederick Mitchell deceased to William Livingston, Surrogate of Kings County, re: request for relief of debts, and the Surrogate court proceedings thereon, of May and June 1809, the originals having been signed by Dorothy Mitchell, William Livingston, and Richard Cromwell.
- Declarations of Sale from the Village of Brooklyn to Samuel Jackson, Clarence D. Sackett, and George Hicks, 1830 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  Three Declarations of Sale conveying property on Henry and Fulton Streets from the president and trustees of the Village of Brooklyn to Samuel Jackson, Clarence D. Sackett, and George Hicks, the sale made due to uncollected taxes, the declaration signed by president of the Board, Joseph Sprague, and Charles [J.] Doughty, clerk.
- Samuel B.M. Sands estate receipts, 1836-1846 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  Two receipts accounting for debts paid by the Estate of Samuel B.M. Sands. 1846 cover sheet, certifying payments re: the estate of Samuel B. M. Sands, signed by Brooklyn treasurer John S. Doughty, street commissioner William Meeker, and L.I. Insurance Co. secretary E.C. Finn, bound with ribbon to ND accounting, copy on identical stationary, of obligations paid by the estate of Samuel B.M. Sands, 1835-1845, covering over 110 items on 23 pages, amounts and signatories given, with some details of biographical, genealogical, corporate/business, or municipal Brooklyn interest. Individuals mentioned include Henry Cruse Murphy, John F. Garrison, Thomas Frazier, Ralph Malbone, Andrew Demarest, Gabriel Furman, William Laurence, Cornelius Suydam, William Augustus Muhlenberg, Henry J. Wyckoff, Elisha W. King, S. Alpheus Smith, et al., also with 1836 classified newspaper advertisement of notice by Magdalen Sands as administratrix, affixed; and a circa 1845 copy, accounting of receipts endorsed on bond of Samuel B.M. Sands, 1836-1844, on behalf of Robert Carter (signed by Carter, R. Sands Tucker, William B. Cooper, and William Hy Carter), Rachel Berry and Elizabeth Rutledge (signed by Berry), and Isaac U. Coles (signed by W. W. Townsend).
- Jeromus Ryerson estate Power of Administration, 1792 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Power of Administration granted by Kings County surrogate Johannis E. Lott to John Van der Bilt (Vanderbilt) and Martin Ryerson, re: the estate of Jeromus Ryerson.
- Clement D. March letter, 1841 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Letter from C.D. (Clement Dudley) March at Alton, IL, to Messrs. Murray & Brand at Chicago re: a debt owed by his brother.
- Jackson, Hicks, and Sackett property map, 1825 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Map of property situated in Brooklyn and owned by Samuel Jackson, George Hicks, and the heirs of the late Samuel Sacket (Sackett), surveyed by Jeremiah Lott, the property extending westward from Fulton Street and south of Clarke (Clark) Street.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Map is in three pieces and should be handled with care.
- Thomas H. March bill of exchange and notarial document, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Bill of exchange from Thomas H. March at Chicago to Murray & Brand, attached to a notarial document of protest at non-payment, signed by Van Wyck Graham at New York.
  Notarial document is in two fragments and should be handled with care.
- Joshua S. March bill of accounting, 1842 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Bill of accounting from Joshua Sands March at Brooklyn to Joseph Potter, attached to 1844 note from Potter re: this bill, witnessed by Alfred G. Stevens, commissioner of Deeds, at Brooklyn.